Guide to the John Burroughs Papers, 1850-1991 (bulk 1860-1921)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES V. CORRESPONDENCE: INCOMING, 1850-1928
  - Family: Burroughs, Julian
    - 1 June 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.9)
    - 23 June 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.10)
    - July 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.11)
    - 2 Aug 1911, (2 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.12)
    - 7 Aug 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.13)
    - 11 Aug 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.14)
    - 24 Aug 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.15)
    - 27 Aug 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.16)
    - 29 Aug 1911, (1 letter,1 annotated) (Folder 27.17)
    - Sep 1911, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.18)
    - Oct 1911, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.19)
    - Jan 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.20)
    - 5-7 Feb 1912, (2 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 27.21)
    - 19-24 Feb 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.22)
    - 2-5 Mar 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.23)
    - 26-18 Mar 1912, (2 letters, 1 photocopy, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.24)
    - Apr 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.25)
    - June 1912, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.26)
    - 5-16 July 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.27)
    - 20-26 July 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.28)
    - 1-6 Aug 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.29)
    - 16-28 Aug 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.30)
    - Sep 1912, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 27.31)
    - Nov 1912, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 27.32)
    - Dec 1912, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 27.33)
    - Feb 1913, (1 letter, 1 annotated, 1 photocopy) (Folder 27.34)
    - May 1913, (1 letter, 1 annotated, 1 photocopy) (Folder 27.35)
    - 1-19 July 1913, (3 letters, 3 annotated, 1 photocopy) (Folder 28.1)
    - 24-28 July 1913, (2 letters, 1 postcard, 3 annotated) (Folder 28.2)
    - 1-7 Aug 1913, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.3)
    - 12-21 Aug 1913, (2 letters, 1 photocopy, 1 postcard, 3 annotated) (Folder 28.4)
    - 11-20 Sep 1913, (2 letters, 1 photocopy, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.5)
    - 25-19 Sep 1913, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.6)
    - Oct 1913, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.7)
    - circa Jan 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.8)
    - 12-20 Jan 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.9)
    - 25-27 Jan 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.10)
    - Feb 1914, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 28.11)
    - 8-9 Mar 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.12)
    - 21-25 Mar 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.13)
    - circa July 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.14)
    - July 1914, (2 letters, 1 photocopy, 3 annotated) (Folder 28.15)
    - 3-16 Aug 1914, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 28.16)
    - 20-31 Aug 1914, (2 postcards, 1 letter, 3 annotated) (Folder 28.17)
    - Sep 1914, (2 letters, 2 enclosure, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.18)
    - Oct 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.19)
    - Dec 1914, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 28.20)
    - circa Dec 1914/, (1 letter,1 annotated) (Folder 28.21)
    - Jan 1915, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 28.22)
    - Feb 1915, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 28.23)
    - Mar 1915, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 28.24)
    - circa June 1915, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 28.25)
    - July 1915, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.1)
    - 3-14 Aug 1915, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.2)
    - 16-28 Aug 1915, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.3)
    - 2-10 Sep 1915, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.4)
    - 15-21 Sep 1915, (3 letters, 3 annotated, 3 enclosure) (Folder 29.5)
    - Oct 1915, (2 letters, 1 enclosure, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.6)
    - Dec 1915, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 29.7)
    - 1-7 Jan 1916, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.8)
    - 12-16 Jan 1916, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.9)
    - Feb-Mar 1916, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.10)
    - 21-26 July 1916, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.11)
    - 29-30 July 1916, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.12)
    - 8-14 Aug 1916, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.13)
    - 21-26 Aug 1916, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.14)
    - Sep 1916, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 29.15)
    - 4-11 Oct 1916, (2 letters, 2 postcards, 4 annotated) (Folder 29.16)
    - 12-16 Oct 1916, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.17)
    - Feb 1917, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 29.18)
    - Mar 1917, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.19)
    - circa June 1917, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 29.20)
    - 6-16 July 1917, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.21)
    - 20-25 July 1917, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 29.22)
    - 28-30 July 1917, (2 letters, 1 enclosure, 2 annotated) (Folder 29.23)
    - 2-8 Aug 1917, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 30.1)
    - 13-30 Aug 1917, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.2)
    - 6-7 Sep 1917, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 30.3)
    - 8-17 Sep 1917, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 30.4)
    - 22-24 Jan 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.5)
    - 25-29 Jan 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.6)
    - 1-6 Feb 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.7)
    - 11-27 Feb 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.8)
    - Mar-June 1918, (2 letters, 1 enclosure, 2 annotated) (Folder 30.9)
    - July 1918, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 30.10)
    - Aug 1918, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 30.11)
    - 2-10 Sep 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.12)
    - 16-24 Sep 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.13)
    - 27-29 Sep 1918, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 30.14)
    - 3-12 Oct 1918, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 30.15)
    - 14-24 Oct 1918, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 31.1)
    - Dec 1918, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 31.2)
    - Feb 1919, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 31.3)
    - Mar 1919, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.4)
    - June 1919, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 31.5)
    - 6-18 July 1919, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.6)
    - 21-30 July 1919, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.7)
    - Aug 1919, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 31.8)
    - Sep 1919, (3 letters, 1 enclosure, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.9)
    - Oct 1919, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.10)
    - Dec 1919, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 31.11)
    - June 1920, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 31.12)
    - 7-10 July 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.13)
    - 19-30 July 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.14)
    - 4-9 Aug 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.15)
    - 10-12 Aug 1920, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 31.16)
    - 14-20 Aug 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.17)
    - 22-30 Aug 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.18)
    - 14-17 Sep 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 31.19)
    - 27-29 Sep 1920, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 31.20)
    - Oct 1920, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 31.21)
    - 1-14 Dec 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 32.1)
    - 20-24 Dec 1920, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 32.2)
    - Jan 1921, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.3)
    - circa Jan 1921, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 32.4)
    - 3-10 Feb 1921, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.5)
    - 18-23 Feb 1921, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 32.6)
    - Mar 1921, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 32.7)
  - Family: Burroughs, Margaret
    - 1885 - May 1904, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.8)
    - Oct 1904 - Jan 1913, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.9)
    - Feb 1913 - 1917, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.10)
  - Family: Burroughs, Maria
    - 1865, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 32.11)
  - Family: Burroughs, Ursula
    - 1863, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 32.12)
    - Jan-July 1864, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 32.13)
    - July-Sep 1864, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.14)
    - 1865 - June 1870, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 32.15)
    - July 1870, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.16)
    - Aug 1870 - July 1871, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 32.17)
    - Oct 1871 - Jan 1873, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 32.18)
    - Feb 1873, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 32.19)
    - Mar-June 1873, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 32.20)
    - Sep 1873 - Aug 1876, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.21)
    - Sep 1876, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 32.22)
    - Oct 1876 - Mar 1881, (5 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 32.23)
    - Aug 1889, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 32.24)
    - 1899-1908, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 32.25)
  - Family: Corbin, Abigail
    - 1861-1875, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.1)
    - 1877-1881, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.2)
    - 1882 - Sep 1884, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.3)
    - Oct-Nov 1884, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.4)
    - Dec 1884-1889, (3 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 33.5)
    - 1897 - Sep 1900, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.6)
    - Nov-Dec 1900, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 33.7)
  - Family: Corbin, Hiram
    - Mar 1877, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 33.8)
  - Family: Covert, Hud H.
    - Feb 1921, (1 transcript, 1 annotated) (Folder 33.9)
  - Family: Deyoe, Chaney
    - 1864 - Feb 1866, (5 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 33.10)
    - Dec 1866 - Feb 1868, (5 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.11)
    - Apr-Dec 1868, (4 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 33.12)
    - Feb-May 1869, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.13)
    - June-Oct 1869, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.14)
    - Jan-July 1870, (3 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 33.15)
    - May-Oct 1870, (4 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.16)
    - Jan-July 1871, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.17)
    - Aug-Nov 1871, (6 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.18)
    - Apr-May 1872, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 33.19)
    - July-Sep 1872, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.20)
    - Oct 1872 - Jan 1873, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.21)
    - Feb-Apr 1873, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.22)
    - July-Oct 1873, (4 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.23)
    - Nov 1873 - Feb 1874, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 33.24)
    - Mar-May 1874, (5 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 33.25)
  - Family: Deyoe, Walker
    - Sep 1874, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.1)
  - Family: Kelley, John
    - Aug 1882, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.2)
  - Family: Lynch Homer
    - 1876-1885, (5 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 34.3)
  - Family: Lynch, Mary Jane
    - 1878-1905, (4 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 34.4)
    - 1907-1911, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 34.5)
  - Family: McGregor, Smith
    - 1919, (2 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.6)
  - Family: [Minerva]
    - 1856, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.7)
  - Family: Montgomery, D.C.
    - 1903, (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.8)
  - Family: North, Amanda
    - 1863-1864, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 34.9)
  - Family: Smith, Julia and Mary Richtryer
    - 1901, (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.10)
  - Family: Zorn, Amy and Will
    - 1908-1909, (2 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 34.11)
  - Others: Clara Barrus
    - 1904-Apr 1907, (8 letters) (Folder 34.12)
    - May-June 1907, (9 letters) (Folder 34.13)
    - July-Aug 1907, (7 letters) (Folder 34.14)
    - Sep-Dec 1907, (15 letters) (Folder 34.15)
    - 1908-1909, (10 letters) (Folder 34.16)
    - Jan-Feb 1910, (4 letters) (Folder 34.17)
    - Mar 1910, (4 letters) (Folder 35.1)
    - 1-11 Apr 1910, (4 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 35.2)
    - 20-29 Apr 1910, (4 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 35.3)
    - 1-5 May 1910, (4 letters, 6 postcards) (Folder 35.4)
    - 6-22 May 1910, (3 letters, 1 fragment) (Folder 35.5)
    - 23-30 May 1910, (2 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 35.6)
    - 1-5 June 1910, (2 letters) (Folder 35.7)
    - 14-16 June 1910, (3 letters) (Folder 35.8)
    - 17-25 June 1910, (3 letters) (Folder 35.9)
    - 5-12 July 1910, (4 letters, 5 enclosures) (Folder 35.10)
    - 16-24 July 1910, (3 letters) (Folder 35.11)
    - 28-30 July 1910, (2 letters, 1 fragment) (Folder 35.12)
    - Aug 1910, (6 letters) (Folder 35.13)
    - 1-11 Sep 1910, (3 letters) (Folder 35.14)
    - 12-20 Sep 1910, (3 letters) (Folder 35.15)
    - 21-29 Sep 1910, (3 letters, 1 postcard, 1 enclosure) (Folder 35.16)
    - 1-12 Oct 1910, (4 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 35.17)
    - 23-30 Oct 1910, (3 letters, 1 enclosure) (Folder 35.18)
    - Nov 1910, (6 letters, 1 postcard, 1 enclosure) (Folder 36.1)
    - Dec 1910, (4 letters) (Folder 36.2)
    - Jan 1911, (3 letters) (Folder 36.3)
    - Mar-Apr 1911, (4 letters, 9 postcards) (Folder 36.4)
    - May 1911, (5 letters) (Folder 36.5)
    - June 1911, (7 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 36.6)
    - 9-18 Oct 1911, (4 letters, 2 postcards, 1 enclosure) (Folder 36.7)
    - 20-27 Oct 1911, (4 letters) (Folder 36.8)
    - Nov 1911, (4 letters, 3 enclosure) (Folder 36.9)
    - Dec 1911, (6 letters) (Folder 36.10)
    - Jan 1912, (4 letters) (Folder 36.11)
    - Feb 1912, (3 letters) (Folder 36.12)
    - Mar 1912, (5 letters) (Folder 36.13)
    - Apr 1912, (5 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 36.14)
    - May 1912, (8 letters, 8 postcards) (Folder 36.15)
    - June 1912, (6 letters) (Folder 36.16)
    - July-Sep 1912, (5 letters, 1 enclosure) (Folder 36.17)
    - Oct 1912, (4 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 37.1)
    - Nov 1912, (2 letters) (Folder 37.2)
    - Dec 1912, (6 letters) (Folder 37.3)
    - circa Dec 1912, (1 letter, fragile) (Folder 37.4)
    - Jan 1913, (4 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 37.5)
    - Feb 1913, (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 37.6)
    - Mar 1913, (5 letters, 1 fragment) (Folder 37.7)
    - Apr-May 1913, (6 letters) (Folder 37.8)
    - June-July 1913, (5 letters) (Folder 37.9)
    - Oct-Dec 1913, (7 letters) (Folder 37.10)
    - Jan-Mar 1914, (5 letters) (Folder 37.11)
    - Apr 1914, (7 letters) (Folder 37.12)
    - May-June 1914, (2 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 37.13)
    - Feb 1915, (5 letters) (Folder 37.14)
    - Mar 1915, (3 letters) (Folder 37.15)
    - Oct-Dec 1915, (7 letters) (Folder 37.16)
    - Jan 1916, (9 letters) (Folder 37.17)
    - Feb-Mar 1916, (6 letters, 1 postcard, 1 enclosure) (Folder 37.18)
    - June-July 1916, (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 37.19)
    - Aug 1916, (8 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 37.20)
    - Sep 1916, (5 letters) (Folder 38.1)
    - Oct 1916, (2 letters) (Folder 38.2)
    - 5-14 Nov 1916, (4 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 38.3)
    - 20-28 Nov 1916, (5 letters) (Folder 38.4)
    - Dec 1916, (2 letters) (Folder 38.5)
    - Feb 1917, (7 letters) (Folder 38.6)
    - 1-12 Mar 1917, (7 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 38.7)
    - 13-15 Mar 1917, (3 letters) (Folder 38.8)
    - June 1917, (6 letters) (Folder 38.9)
    - Oct 1917, (4 letters) (Folder 38.10)
    - Jan-July 1918, (4 letters, 1 postcard, 1 enclosure) (Folder 38.11)
    - Aug-Dec 1918, (2 letters) (Folder 38.12)
    - Feb-Apr 1919, (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 38.13)
    - Oct 1919, (4 letters, 2 postcards, 2 enclosure) (Folder 38.14)
    - Nov-Dec 1919, (4 letters) (Folder 38.15)
    - 1920, (2 letters) (Folder 38.16)
    - undated, (1 letter) (Folder 38.17)
    - 1901, (9 typescripts) (Folder 38.18)
    - 1902, (59 typescripts) (Folder 38.19)
    - 1903, (19 typescripts) (Folder 38.20)
  - Others: Miscellaneous, Alphabetical by Name
    - Allaben, Adelbert Edwin, 1901-1907; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.1)
    - Allaben, Sarah C. "Cattie,", 1856, 1884-1901; (4 letters, 1 photoprint of a letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.2)
    - Allen, E.M., 28 June 1867; (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 50.9)
    - Baldwin, Elsie, 1908, undated; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.3)
    - Barnard, Vincent, 1866-1868; (3 letters) (Folder 39.4)
    - Barrett, Charles, 1906-1917; (3 letters) (Folder 39.5)
    - Barrus, Eleanor, 1913-1916; (4 letters) (Folder 39.6)
    - Beal, Mary, 1909-1921; (9 letters,2 postcards, 4 annotated, 1 photocopy) (Folder 49.25)
    - Beane, Samuel C., 1910; (3 letters) (Folder 39.7)
    - Beardslee, Amelia H., 1881; (2 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.8)
    - Beardslee, Amelia H., 1882; (3 letters) (Folder 39.9)
    - Beardslee, Amelia H., 1883-1884; (2 letters) (Folder 39.10)
    - Bigelow, Poultney, 1915; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.11)
    - Bigelow, Poultney, 1917-1919; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.12)
    - Bigelow, Poultney, 1920; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 39.13)
    - Bigelow, Poultney, 1921-1928; (6 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.14)
    - Bogart, Egbert - school friend, Nov 1855, March 1856; (2 letter, 2 annotated) (Folder 49.15)
    - Buck, Louise Bacorn, 1900-1910, undated; (11 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.15)
    - Carman, Bliss, 1909; (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.16)
    - Childs, John Lewis, 1911-1919; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.17)
    - Cline, May, undated; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.18)
    - Craig, Evelyn, 1912-1917; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.19)
    - Custer, Elizabeth B., 1902-1917; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.20)
    - De Loach, Richard, 1904- Feb 1916; (4 letters, 4 postcards, 2 photos, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.21)
    - De Loach, Richard, March 1916- 1917; (6 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.22)
    - Drake, Mary Aiken, 1908-1909; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.23)
    - Edison, Mina Miller, 1916-1918; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.24)
    - Edwards, Frederick T., 1916-1917; (3 letters) (Folder 39.25)
    - Elliot, Charles Norton, 1911-1912; (3 letters) (Folder 39.26)
    - Fisher, G. Clyde, 1917-1920; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.27)
    - Fletcher, Lisa A., 1891-1892; (4 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 39.28)
    - Funk, I.K., 1907; (1 letter) (Folder 39.29)
    - Gilbert, E.S., 1877 (Folder 49.7)
    - Gilbert, E.S., 1878 (Folder 49.8)
    - Gilbert, E.S., 1879 (Folder 49.9)
    - Gilbert, E.S., 1880 (Folder 49.10)
    - Gilbert, E.S., 1881-1882 (Folder 49.11)
    - Gilbert, E.S., 1884-1890, undated (Folder 49.12)
    - Gilbert, Frances and Olive, 1903; (3 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 39.30)
    - Hagedorn, Hermann, 1919; (1 letter, 1 draft reply from J.B., 1 annotated) (Folder 39.31)
    - Haight, Elizabeth Hazelton, 1920; (1 letter) (Folder 39.32)
    - Harris, Theodora Peck, 1913-1915; (2 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.33)
    - Hasbrouck, Jon, 1866-1869; (5 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 39.34)
    - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1868-1889; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.1)
    - Hornor, C.G., 1910-1914; (3 letters, 1 reply from J.B., 1 annotated) (Folder 40.2)
    - Hull, A.G., 1863, 1882; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 49.16)
    - Ingersoll, Ernest, 1874-1890, undated; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.3)
    - Jenkins, Cora, 1902-1909; (5 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.4)
    - Johns, Aaron, 1877-1883; (6 letters, 1 postcard, 2 annotated) (Folder 40.5)
    - Johnson, Addie Barrus, 1910-1912; (1 letter, 2 postcards) (Folder 40.6)
    - Johnson, Clifton, 1903-1920; (6 letters) (Folder 50.2)
    - Keck, Charles H., 1919; (1 letter) (Folder 40.7)
    - Keeler, Charles, 1900-1915; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.8)
    - Kennan, George and Eveline, 1913-1918; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.9)
    - Kinne, B.B. - of the Middletown Sanitarium re: Ursula Burroughs, 31 Oct 1916; (1 letter) (Folder 49.13)
    - Laing, William O., 1912; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.10)
    - Lazarus, Emma, 1878-1885; (9 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.11)
    - Liebold, E.G., 1917-1920; (6 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.12)
    - Lindsay, Frank B., 1913-1919; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.13)
    - Loveman, Robert, 1914-1920; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.14)
    - Lummis, Charles F., 1920; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.15)
    - Lwoff-Parlaghy, Princess, undated; (1 letter [photocopy]) (Folder 40.16)
    - McCarthy, John Russell, 1919-1921; (7 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.17)
    - Miles, Herbert D., 1919-1920; (4 letters, 1 reply from J.B.) (Folder 40.18)
    - Moore, James, 1917-1920; (7 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.19)
    - Morgan, Mary, 1902-1905; (5 letters, 3 manuscripts, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.20)
    - Morgan, Mary, 1906-1910, undated; (5 letters, 1 manuscript) (Folder 40.21)
    - Murland, Marie, 1908-1909; (4 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.22)
    - Murphy, A.M., 1919; (1 letter) (Folder 40.23)
    - Norton, J. Pease, 1907-1908; (1 letter, 1 certificate) (Folder 40.24)
    - Oswald, Felix L., 1881; (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 40.25)
    - Owen, William and Mary, 1899-1900; (4 letters) (Folder 40.26)
    - Owings, Chloe, 1917; (4 letters) (Folder 40.27)
    - Paine, L. B. - Cooperstown friend, 1 Aug 1850, 15 Aug 1856; (1 letter, 1 photocopy, 2 copies of photoprint) (Folder 49.14)
    - Peck, Ludella L., 1891; (2 letters) (Folder 40.28)
    - Peck, Ludella L., 1892; (7 letters) (Folder 40.29)
    - Peck, Ludella L., 1893-1895; (5 letters) (Folder 40.30)
    - Peck, Ludella L., 1896-1900; (6 letters) (Folder 40.31)
    - Peck, Ludella L., 1901-1902; (4 letters) (Folder 41.1)
    - Peck, Ludella L., 1903-1912; (6 letters) (Folder 41.2)
    - Perkins, Maude B., 1918; (1 letter) (Folder 41.3)
    - Piatt, John J., 1870-1880, undated; (6 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.4)
    - Rickert, Edith, 1902-1921; (12 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.5)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1893-1911; (photocopies and transcripts) (Folder 41.6)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 27 Sep 1905; (1 letter, 1 transcript) (Folder 50.5)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, via William Loeb, Jr., Secretary to the President, 2 Feb 1906; (1 photocopy) (Folder 50.6)
    - Shannon, Thomas N., 1917-1921; (4 letters) (Folder 41.7)
    - Sherman, Ellen Burns, 1912-1913; (4 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 41.8)
    - Shoemaker, W.L., 1872-1877; (6 letters, 7 annotated) (Folder 41.9)
    - Shoemaker, W.L., 1878-1881; (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 41.10)
    - Smith, Alexander ("Sandy"), 1905-1919; (5 letters, 1 postcard, 2 annotated) (Folder 41.11)
    - Stephens, C.A., 1909-1910; (3 letters) (Folder 41.12)
    - Taylor, Sarah K., 1884-1885; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.13)
    - Taylor, William, 1906-1920; (7 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.14)
    - Tolman, Adams, 1919; (1 letter, 1 reply from J.B.) (Folder 41.15)
    - University of Georgia — Commencement Invitation, 1911 (Folder 50.10)
    - Walton, E. Clayton, 1913-1920; (4 letters) (Folder 41.16)
    - White, Orlando, 1902-1916; (4 letters, 1 reply from J.B., 2 annotated) (Folder 41.17)
    - White, Orlando, 1919-1921; (6 letters) (Folder 41.18)
    - Whitman, Walt, 1889; (1 letter) (Folder 41.19)
    - Willis, Bailey, 1909-1910; (3 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.20)
    - Winters, Lora Leonard, 1905-1920; (5 letters, 2 postcards, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.21)
    - Woodworth, Nelly Hart, circa 1897-1910; (4 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 41.22)
    - Wright, Silas H., 1877-1885; (6 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 41.23)
  - Others: Miscellaneous, by Category
    - From Academics
      - Bailey, Liberty Hyde (Cornell) (Folder 41.24)
      - Beers, Harry A. (Yale) (Folder 41.24)
      - Butler, Nicholas Murray (Columbia) (Folder 41.24)
      - Curtis, Fred J. (Curtis School) (Folder 41.24)
      - Finley, John H. (University of the State of New York) (Folder 41.25)
      - Lounsbury, Thomas R. (Yale) (Folder 41.25)
      - Schultz. John Richie (Allegheny College) (Folder 41.25)
    - Regarding Accepting the Universe
      - Bruun, Charles A. (Folder 41.26)
      - Cooke, Charles H. (Folder 41.26)
      - Decker, Frank H. (Folder 42.1)
      - Duncan, William J. (Folder 42.1)
      - Levey, M. J. (Folder 42.1)
      - Lint, Perry A. (Folder 42.1)
      - Lyons, Alexander (Folder 42.1)
      - McIntosh, J. E. (Folder 42.2)
      - McJunkin, Robert A. (Folder 42.2)
      - Patterson, R. S. (Folder 42.2)
    - Expressing Appreciation
      - Alger - Mapes, (27 letters) (Folder 54.14)
      - Martin - Williams, (36 letters) (Folder 54.15)
    - From Artists
      - Boughton, Alice (Folder 42.3)